开始读数
Start your reading.
我都想住在这里了，吉姆
Well, I just might stake out a claim and settle down here, Jim.
- 确实很美妙 - 真不想破坏这美景
- It is spectacular, isn't it? - It's a shame to have to intrude.
上一艘侦查舰传回一些不寻常的感应器读数
Well, the last scout ship reported some pretty strange sensor readings.
星际舰队要求调查这里，并与当地居民取得联系
Starfleet wants it investigated and the inhabitants contacted.
按命令行事就是了
We'll do what we're told.
舰长，这里的土壤十分肥沃
The soil here is remarkably rich and fertile, captain.
非常适合开发农业
Husbandry would be quite efficacious.
你确定？
You sure about that?
非常确定
Oh, quite sure.
读数显示，整个星球都被这种植被覆盖
Readings indicate the entire planet is covered with growth like this.
真奇怪，就算是极地，气温差异也很小
Curious. Even at the poles there's very little variation in temperature,
这个星球的平均温度是华氏76度
which maintains a planet-wide average of 76 degrees.
我明白，几乎不可能
I know. Almost impossible.
我想家了，这里就像俄罗斯一样
It makes me homesick. Just like Russia.
更像是伊甸园吧，少尉
More like the Garden of Eden, ensign.
当然了医生，伊甸园就在莫斯科郊外
Of course, doctor. The Garden of Eden was just outside Moscow.
一个很美丽的地方
A very nice place.
亚当和夏娃离开的时候肯定很伤心
It must have made Adam and Eve very sad to leave.
就在莫斯科郊外，好吧
Just outside Moscow. All right.
距离232方位17公里处有一个村子
There's a village about 17 kilometres away on bearing 232.
我们往那走
We'll head that way.
舰长
Captain.
死了
Dead.
是谁说的？
What did somebody say?
这就是天堂的模样？
That paradise must have looked like this?
宇宙，最后的边疆
Space, the final frontier.
这是星舰进取号的航程
These are the voyages of the starship Enterprise.
它的五年任务，是去探索未知的新世界
Its five-year mission: To explore strange new worlds,
找寻新的生命与新的文明
to seek out new life and new civilisations,
勇敢的航向前人未至之境
to boldly go where no man has gone before.
【星际迷航：原初】
-=THE LAST FANTASY=-荣誉出品
本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业途径
-=TLF字幕组=-
翻译：诺阿诺阿
校对：喜马拉雅
第二季第五集
亚当的苹果
舰长日志，星历3715.3
Captain's log, stardate 3715.3.
我们在未探索过的三角座γ六号进行常规勘察时
While making a routine exploration of the unexplored Gamma Trianguli VI,
一名队员被有毒植物射死
one of my men has been killed by a poisonous plant.
等我们离开这里，立刻把遗体传送回去
As soon as we get out of the way, beam the body up.
遵命，舰长，亨德夫先生的死真是让人遗憾
Aye, captain. It's a shame about Hendorff.
- 我们看来也有麻烦了 - 怎么了？
- We seem to have a problem too. - What is it?
我们的反物质隔舱正在失效
We're losing potency in our antimatter pods.
我认为问题不严重，不过我们正在调查
I don't think it's serious, but we're looking into it.
- 是什么原因引起的？ - 我不确定，舰长
- What's causing it? - I'm not sure, sir.
我们测量了这个星球的电磁场
But we've run measurements on the electromagnetic field of the planet,
发现有一点点反常
and they are a wee bit abnormal.
可能跟这个有关系
That might have something to do with it.
不过你说没什么好担心的？
But you say there's nothing to worry about?
舰长，严格来讲我没有这么说
Well, sir, I didn't exactly say that.
保持现状，等我们先完成地面的工作
Stay on top of it. We got a job to do here, might as well finish it.
听说下面不错
I hear it's nice down there.
是不错
Yeah. It's nice.
多加小心，应该不会有什么麻烦了
If we're a little more careful, we shouldn't run into any more trouble.
我也可以去下面的花园里
I could do with a nice walk in a garden
看看绿叶和青草
with green leaves and grass.
花园散步的事交给我们，史考特 你负责反物质隔舱的事就好
We'll do the walking, Scotty. You get on the antimatter pod.
如果情况恶化，通知我，我们会赶回去，完毕
If it gets any worse, let me know, we'll beam up. Kirk out.
这种情况不寻常啊，舰长
I find that most unusual, captain.
史考特会处理好的，我们还有工作要做
Scotty will handle it. We've got a job to do.
你的三录仪上有情况吗？
Turn up anything on your tricorder?
有，各个方向都出现了地下震动，绵延数英里
Indeed. Subsurface vibrations for miles in all directions.
真奇怪
That's strange.
十分强烈，非常规律，是人为造成的
Quite strong, fairly regular, artificially produced.
马洛里
Mallory.
是，舰长
Yes, captain.
我们向村庄前进，避免与类人生物接触
We're heading for the village. Avoid contact with the humanoids,
我要你跟马普尔做一番全面侦查
but I want you and Marple to make a full reconnaissance,
小心点，除了有毒的植物，可能还有其他危险
so be careful. There may be other danger besides poisonous plants.
- 保持联系 - 是，舰长
- Keep in constant communication. - Aye, sir.
舰长
Captain.
怎么了？
What is it?
就在我们正前方，藏着一个类人生物
There's a humanoid hiding directly behind us,
移动非常敏捷，方向18
moving with remarkable agility, bearing 18.
- 是什么，史波克先生 - 一位拜访者
- What is it, Mr. Spock? - A visitor,
应该说是，一位不想透露姓名的人
and one wanting to retain his anonymity, I should say.
一切都这么美
All this beauty,
可是现在亨德夫先生死了，还有人在监视我们…
and now Mr. Hendorff dead, somebody watching us...
真是让人害怕
It's frightening.
如果你一定要担心
If you insist on worrying,
就担心担心我吧
worry about me.
我一直都想带你来这样美丽的地方
I've been wanting to get you in a place like this for a long time.
契诃夫先生，兰登文书，我明白你们俩彼此吸引
Mr. Chekov, Yeoman Landon, I know you find each other fascinating,
可我们不是来这里研究人类生物学方面的田野调查的
but we're not here to conduct a field experiment in human biology.
我这就去测数据
I was just about to take some readings.
- 发现什么了吗？ - 不管是什么，这东西都像猫一样敏捷
- Anything? - Whatever it is, it moves like a cat.
吉姆，我不喜欢这样
Jim, I don't like this.
我也不喜欢，全体都有
Neither do I. All hands.
我们被盯上了，我们可能被盯上了
We've been watched, we'll probably be watched.
呈L队形开始行动
We're moving out. Formation L.
有意思，比重极低
Interesting. Extremely low specific gravity.
含有沥青铀矿，角闪石以及石英
Some uraninite, hornblende, quartz.
很脆，断面整齐，分析一番应该会很有趣
Fragile, good cleavage. An analysis should prove interesting.
史波克，你扔东西的时候能不能小心一点？
Would you mind being careful where you throw your rocks, Spock?
看来这石头性质极不稳定，舰长
Obviously highly unstable, captain.
这可能是个很重要发现
This could be a find of some importance.
如果量大，可能会是很重要的能量来源
In large quantities, it could be a considerable source of power.
埋着地雷的伊甸园
A Garden of Eden with land mines.
进取号呼叫寇克舰长
Enterprise to Captain Kirk.
- 收到 - 我是史考特
- Kirk here. - Scott, sir.
我们的反物质隔舱完全失效了
Our antimatter pods are completely inert.
无法阻止，不过我知道原因了
I couldn't stop it, but I know why.
是什么？
Why?
是来自星球表面的某种物质，像是往火上浇了一桶水
Something from the surface. Like a pail of water on a fire.
某种电波或者传动装置，而且仍在继续
A beam, maybe, or a transmission. And it's still on.
我分析过了
I'm having it analysed,
但是我从来没见过这种东西
but it's like nothing I've ever seen before.
来自我们定位到的地表村庄
And it's pinpointed in the area of that village we located down there.
我们正前往村庄，史考特，你需要帮助吗？
We're heading there now, Scotty. Do you need any help?
你们也无能为力，先生
There's nothing you can do about it, sir.
看起来暂时不会有危险
There doesn't seem to be any immediate danger.
好吧，我们会尽力搞清楚下面的情况，完毕
All right, Scotty, we'll try and find out what's going on down here. Kirk out.
如果史考特关于地表力量的猜想是正确的
If Scott is correct about the force from the surface,
可能跟我刚才探测到的震动有关
it may have to do with the vibrations I read earlier.
某种发动机？
Some kind of generator?
如果是，肯定十分巨大，可能在地下
If so, an immense one. Probably subterranean.
那是什么？
What's that?
植物的刺，像是杀死亨德夫的那种
Some of the thorns like those that killed Hendorff.
看到顶端的这个了吗？
See this stuff on the end?
像是皂角苷，只不过比那厉害千倍
It's like saponin, only it's a thousand times stronger.
天堂里居然有这种东西
Peculiar stuff to find in paradise.
吉姆！
Jim!
史波克！
Spock!
安全警戒
Security alert.
他还活着吗？
Is he alive?
我给他注射了足够让咱们所有人都倒下的玛斯弗D
I filled him with enough Masiform D to make the whole crew turn handsprings
他都没有反应，得让他回舰上，吉姆
and he's not responding. Gotta get him back to the ship, Jim.
- 寇克呼叫进取号 - 史考特收到
- Kirk to Enterprise. - Scott here, sir.
我们即将传送回舰，通知传送室
We're beaming up. Notify Transporter Room.
并安排接马洛里和马普尔回舰
And make arrangements to pick up Mallory and Marple.
我派他们出去侦查了
They're scouting ahead of us.
是，舰长
Aye, aye, sir.
传送室，准备传送陆上分队
Transporter Room, stand by to beam up landing party.
全体都有！
All hands!
准备
Standing by, sir.
供给能量
Energise.
史考特，供给能量
Scotty, energise.
史考特，怎么了？
Scotty, what's the matter?
无法建立传送连接，舰长
We can't make transporter contact, sir.
整个系统都被禁止了
The entire system's inhibited.
按现在这情况，我们连只苍蝇都无法传送
The way it is now, we couldn't beam up a fly.
舰长日志，补充
Captain's log, supplementary.
我们对三角座γ六号的探索
Our investigation of Gamma Trianguli VI
突然间变成了一场噩梦
has suddenly turned into a nightmare.
有人监视跟踪我们，史波克先生也受伤了
We're being watched and followed. Mr. Spock has been injured.
现在又发现我们无法返回星舰
And now we find we are unable to return to the ship.
史考特，传送室故障
Scotty, is the transporter malfunction tied in
是否跟反物质隔舱的问题有关系？
with the trouble you're having with the antimatter pods?
我不知道，先生，我检查一下，然后向你报告
I don't know, sir. I'll check and get back to you.
完毕
Scott out.
史波克
Spock.
你还好吗？
You all right?
麦考伊医生的药剂就像他开的别的药一样
Dr. McCoy's potion is acting like all his potions,
让我倒胃
turning my stomach.
除此之外，我很好
Other than that, I am quite well.
如果你的血液是红色的而不是绿色的
If your blood were red instead of green,
你就不会胃疼了
you wouldn't have an upset stomach.
你刚才想做什么？
Just what do you think you were trying to do?
我想你没有注意那株植物，所以我…
I surmised you were unaware of that plant, so l...
用自己的身体挡住毒刺
Stepped in front and took the thorns yourself.
舰长，我向你保证，我本意不是那样的
I assure you, captain, I had no intention of doing that.
是我反应太慢
It was merely my own clumsiness
所以没有避开
which prevented me from moving out of the way.
我明白了，下次喊我就好了
I see. Well, next time just yell.
我会像别人一样迅速躲开的
I can step out of the way as quickly as the next man.
我会的
I shall do so.
你差点死掉
Trying to get yourself killed.
你知道星际舰队在你身上投资了多少吗？
You know how much Starfleet has invested in you?
- 122,200… - 算了
- 122,200... - Never mind.
不过还是要谢谢你
But thanks.
- 卡普兰，你去接手 - 是
- Kaplan, take the post. - Yes, sir.
不光有人在盯着我们，星舰也被盯上了
Not only is something after us, but it's after the ship as well.
舰长，要如此大范围的影响星舰
Captain, to affect the ship at this extreme range
需要十分复杂精细的星球防御体系
would require a highly sophisticated planetary defence system.
30秒前，天空还一丝云都没有
Thirty seconds ago there wasn't a cloud in the sky.
找掩护！
Take cover!
相位枪
Phasers.
美好的一天啊，史波克先生
A beautiful day, Mr. Spock.
天空没有一丝云
Not a cloud in the sky.
就像天堂一样
Just like paradise.
寇克收到
Kirk here.
舰长，我是马洛里
Mallory here, captain.
我在村庄附近
I'm near the village.
坐标118乘220
Coordinates 118 by 220.
马洛里
Mallory.
马洛里，你还好吗？
Mallory, are you all right? Come in.
村庄很原始
The village is primitive.
表面来看，像是部落
Strictly tribal, from the looks of it.
而且，舰长，还有别的
And, captain, there's something else.
舰长，能听到吗
Captain, come in.
马洛里，马洛里，你还好吗？
Mallory. Mallory, are you all right?
马洛里！
Mallory!
舰长，马洛里所说的坐标就在那个方向不远处
Captain, those coordinates are a short distance in that direction.
快！
On the double.
在这边，我从没见过这种东西
It's over there, that way! I never saw anything like it.
马洛里！
Mallory!
马普尔，退后，小心点
Marple, stand back. Watch it.
是石头
Rocks.
- 舰长 - 亨德夫…
- Captain. - Hendorff...
我认识卡普兰的家人，现在又是马洛里
I know Kaplan's family. Now Mallory.
吉姆，这些都是你无能为力的事
Jim, you couldn't have stopped any of this.
他父亲曾帮助我进入学院
His father helped me get into the academy.
舰长，这些都是无法避免的
Captain, in each case, this was unavoidable.
- 我本可以阻止这些事发生的 - 我不这么认为
- I could've prevented all of it. - I don't see how.
在天堂里散步…
Walk in paradise...
…被鲜花绿草环绕
...among the green grass and the flowers.
我应该在一开始出现问题的时候，就把大家传送回舰
I should've beamed up at the first sign of trouble.
你是受命来这颗星球探索文明的
You are under orders to investigate this planet and this culture.
同样，在认为大家有危险的情况下
I also have the option to disregard those orders
我也可以选择不执行这些命令
if I consider them overly hazardous.
这任务没那么重要，史波克
This isn't that important a mission, Spock,
不值得为之牺牲三条人命
not worth the lives of three of my men.
因为自己喜欢植物生长的味道
I dropped my guard for a minute
我便放松了警惕
because I like the smell of growing things.
现在三个人都牺牲了，星舰也有了麻烦
And now three men are dead, and the ship's in trouble.
星际舰队的任务一向很危险
No one has ever stated that Starfleet duty was particularly safe.
你做出的决定正确且符合逻辑
You've followed the correct and logical course,
尽到了一个指挥官的职责，自责…
done everything a commander could do. Self-recriminations...
舰长
Captain,
我们的朋友就在后面
our friend is back.
马普尔，契诃夫先生，立正
Marple. Mr. Chekov, at attention.
两位，有人或者是某种东西就在我们后面的石头背后
Gentlemen, something or someone is behind that rock.
给我揪出来
I want it.
马普尔，从你的右边绕到石头后面
Marple, cut around the rock, to your right.
动静大点，注意安全
Make a loud noise. Be careful.
史波克，你和契诃夫负责转移注意力…
Spock, you and Chekov create a diversion...
…声音大点
...and make it loud.
契诃夫先生，你的三录仪读数更新太慢了
Mr. Chekov, your tricorder readings are totally inefficient.
管好你自己的事，先生
Mind your own business, sir.
告诉你，我的效率是很高的
For your information, I have a very high efficiency rating.
少尉，我不允许你用这种语气跟我说话
Ensign, I will not have you address me in that tone of voice!
那你想要什么声，小提琴声吗？
What do you want, violins?
我不会伤害你，明白吗？
I won't hurt you. Do you understand?
我不会伤害你
I won't hurt you.
你用拳头…
You struck me...
…打了我
...with your hand.
我不会再打你了
Well, I won't strike you again.
你一直在跟踪监视我们，为什么？
You've been following us, watching us. Why?
我是瓦尔之眼，他必须要看见
I am the Eyes of Vaal. He must see.
瓦尔是谁？
Who is Vaal?
瓦尔就是瓦尔，他是…
Vaal is Vaal. He is...
…万物
...everything.
- 你有名字吗？ - 我叫阿古他
- Do you have a name? - I am Akuta.
我是瓦尔侍奉者的首领
I am the leader of the Feeders of Vaal.
他们不会伤害你的，我保证
They're not going to hurt you, I promise you.
阿古他，阿古他
Akuta. Akuta.
我们是为和平而来
We come in peace.
我们想跟这位瓦尔谈话
We would like to speak to this Vaal.
只有阿古他才能和瓦尔对话
Akuta alone speaks to Vaal.
我是瓦尔的眼和声
I am the eyes and the voice of Vaal.
这是瓦尔的意志
It is Vaal's wish.
舰长，这真是神奇
Captain, this is fascinating.
请允许我，先生
If you will permit me, sir?
天线吗？
Antennae?
那是瓦尔的耳朵
They are my ears for Vaal.
是朦胧时瓦尔赐予我的
They were given to me in the Dim Time,
这样人们就能理解并遵循他的旨意
so the people could understand his commands, and obey.
你说到了瓦尔的子民，他们在附近吗？
You speak of the People of Vaal. Are they nearby?
我们要接近瓦尔，这样才能侍奉他
We are close to Vaal so we may serve him.
我带你们去那里
I shall take you there.
进取号呼叫寇克舰长
Enterprise to Captain Kirk.
寇克收到
Kirk here.
红色警报！红色警报！
Condition Red! Condition Red!
舰长，星球表面的某种物质扼制住了我们
Captain, something has grabbed us from the planet's surface.
就像巨大的牵引光束，我们无法挣脱
Like a giant tractor beam. And we can't break loose.
没用的，史考特，我们快坚持不住了
It's no use, Mr. Scott. We're just barely holding our own.
曲速引擎还不行吗？
Are the warp drives still out?
是的，我们只剩下脉冲引擎了
Aye, sir. All we have is impulse power.
开到最大，打开所有紧急线路
Put it on maximum. Full emergency circuits.
全打开了，舰长
They're all on, captain.
现在情况如何，还坚持的住吗？
Status. Are you still holding?
- 卡尔？ - 没有，仍在下滑
- Kyle. - No, sir. We're slipping.
卡尔，把我们的速度输进计算机看看有什么结果
Computer banks, Kyle. Feed in our rate, get me a figure.
曲速引擎能带我们离开
We might be able to pull out with warp drive, but without it,
没有它我们就如板上鱼肉，任人宰割
we're like a fly on flypaper. Even worse.
情况不妙啊，卡尔，快点给我数据
We're starting to lose ground. Hurry up with the figure, Kyle.
保持反推力全开，抵抗吸引力
Maintain full reverse thrust against the pull.
派人去处理曲速引擎的问题，想办法让引擎工作起来
Put a team on that warp drive. Get it working.
已经派人去了，舰长，他们也没有办法啊
I've done that, captain. They haven't been able to do a thing.
反推力开到最大了，舰长
It's no good, captain.
没什么用
With maximum thrust against the pull,
我们只能保持16个小时全动力
we'll only be able to maintain full power for 16 hours.
16个小时后燃料就殆尽了
Then we burn up for sure.
史考特，你是我的首席轮机长
Scotty, you're my chief engineer.
你对星舰了如指掌
You know everything about that ship there is to know,
甚至比设计星舰的人还要了解
more than the men who designed it.
你要是不能修理好曲速引擎
If you can't get those warp engines working,
就收拾东西回家吧
you're fired.
我会尽力而为的，舰长，完毕
I'll do everything there is to do, sir. Scott out.
跟我说说瓦尔
Tell me about Vaal.
天下人都知道瓦尔
All the world knows about Vaal.
他降甘霖于大地，让阳光普照
He causes the rains to fall, and the sun to shine.
所有美好的事物都是瓦尔的恩赐
All good comes from Vaal.
带我去见他，我想跟他谈话
Take me to him. I wish to speak to him.
我可以带你去见他
I shall take you to him,
但是他不会跟你说话，他只跟我说话
but he will not speak to you. He speaks only to me.
那也要试试
I'll take my chances.
瓦尔
Vaal.
舰长日志，星历3715.6
Captain's log, stardate 3715.6.
我们被带去见瓦尔
We have been introduced to Vaal,
也就是这颗星球的能量来源
evidently the source of the planet's power emanations
而且很可能是威胁到我们以及星舰的力量来源
and possibly the force that threatens both us and our ship.
好神奇啊
Fascinating.
如此技艺精湛的作品，如此古老
A very high order of workmanship. Very ancient.
能够产生巨大的动力
Generating great power.
但这里不是中心，史波克先生
But this is not the centre, Mr. Spock.
确实不是，中心在地下深处
No, captain. The centre is deep in the earth beneath us.
这里是入口
This is an access point.
看来同时也是…
It would also seem to be a...
- 力场？ - 很明显是
- A force field? - Obviously.
- 你还好吧？ - 我很好
- You all right? - Yes, quite.
范围大约是30英尺
It extends some 30 feet beyond the figure in all directions.
成分很常见，十分强大
Conventional in composition, and quite formidable.
阿古他，如何跟瓦尔对话？
Akuta, how do you talk to Vaal?
只有瓦尔唤我时才能跟他对话
Vaal calls me. Only then.
我们无法接近他，无法跟他交谈，除非他想跟我们说话…
Well, we can't get to it, can't talk to it unless it wants to talk to us...
瓦尔现在在睡觉
Vaal sleeps now.
等他饿了，你们或许就可以跟他说话了
When he is hungry, you may be able to speak with him,
当然，如果他愿意的话
if he desires it.
- 那他什么时候饿？ - 很快
- When does he get hungry? - Soon.
来吧，先吃点东西
Come. We will give you food and drink.
要是累了，你们就休息一下
If you are tired, you may rest.
这些就是瓦尔的子民
These are the People of Vaal.
其他人呢？
Where are the others?
没有其他人啊
There are no others.
儿童呢
The children.
儿童？
Children?
我没有听过你说的词
You use unknown words to me.
像你们一样，小一点，会长大的
Little ones, like yourselves. They grow.
啊，你是说替换，我们这里不需要
Replacements. None are necessary.
瓦尔禁止儿童的出现
They are forbidden by Vaal.
可是男女相爱了…
But when a man and woman fall in love...
“爱”
"Love."
好奇怪，“儿童”，“爱”，什么是爱？
Strange words, "children," "love." What is love?
爱就是两个人…
Love is when two people are...
啊，拥抱，触碰之类
Yes, the holding, the touching.
瓦尔也禁止这个
Vaal has forbidden this.
哈，这就是天堂啊
Well, there goes paradise.
这些人远道而来
These people are from another place.
欢迎他们
They have come among us. Welcome them.
欢迎来到瓦尔
Welcome to Vaal.
我们的大门为你敞开
Our homes are open to you.
谢谢你
Well, thank you.
他们送我们这个
It does something for you.
是啊，这让我感觉不自在
Yes, indeed, it does, captain. It makes me uncomfortable.
我是西雅娜，你呢？
I am Sayana. You have a name?
我是史波克
Yes, Spock. I am Spock.
史波克？
Spock?
这有什么好笑的
I fail to see what they find so amusing.
来吧！
Come!
这间屋子是为你们准备的
This house is your house.
我会派人给你们送来吃的和喝的
I will send you more food and drink.
欢迎你们来到瓦尔的领地
You are welcome in the place of Vaal.
现在我们倒受欢迎了
Now we're welcome.
不久前这颗星球还想要我们的命呢
A while ago this whole planet was trying to kill us.
- 这不合理啊 - 这儿没什么是合理的
- It doesn't make sense. - Nothing makes sense down here.
- 寇克呼叫进取号，收到回答 - 史考特收到
- Kirk to Enterprise. Come in. - Scott here.
史考特，报告一下情况
Status report, Scotty.
没有变化，星舰轨道如期衰减
No change, captain. The orbit is decaying along computed lines.
曲速引擎还是不能工作
No success with the warp drive.
我们在下坠，而且没有办法阻止
We're going down and we can't stop it.
我不想再听到“没有办法”这四个字了 想办法让星舰离开那里
I'm sick of hearing that word, "can't." Get that ship out of there.
舰长，我已经做了我能做的一切
Sir, we're doing everything within engineering reason.
那就发挥想象力
Then use your imagination.
把飞船的所有能量都注入脉冲引擎
Tie every ounce of power the ship has into the impulse engines.
必要的时候抛弃曲速引擎短舱
Discard the warp-drive nacelles if you have to,
不管用什么办法都要让星舰逃离那里
and crack out with the main section, but get that ship out of there!
我打算切断生命维持系统之外的一切能源
I'm gonna switch over everything but the life-support systems
来给脉冲引擎提供动力，不过这样也很危险
and boost the impulse power, but that's just about as dangerous.
就这么办，完毕
Do it. Kirk out.
- 难以置信啊 - 报告一下
- Incredible. - Report.
我刚才对这里的土著居民做了一番研究
I just ran a thorough check on the natives,
他们体内完全没有任何有害细菌
and there's a complete lack of harmful bacteria in their systems.
没有脱钙作用，没有组织退化也没有动脉硬化
No decalcification, no degeneration of tissue, no arteriosclerosis.
简单来说，吉姆，他们不会变老
In simple terms, Jim, they're not growing old.
而且我也没办法告诉你他们多大
And I can't begin to tell you how old they are.
有可能是20岁，也有可能是2万岁
Twenty years, or 20,000 years.
我知道了
I see.
有什么想法
Opinion.
很有可能，这与我做的大气分析相符合
Quite possible. It checks with my atmospheric analysis.
这里的大气层过滤了所有阳光的负面影响
Their atmosphere completely negates any harmful effects from their sun.
再加上这里简单的饮食
Add to that a simple diet,
宜人的温度，也没有天敌
perfectly controlled temperature, no natural enemies,
没有什么恶习，也就没有必要新陈代谢
apparently no vices, no replacements needed...
也许这里真的是天堂
Maybe it is paradise after all.
史波克
Mr. Spock.
看来我们的猜测是正确的，那里面没有什么活物
Apparently our hypothesis is correct. There is no living being there.
那是个机器，仅此而已
It is a machine, nothing more.
力场消失了，人们可以进去了
Well, the field's down, people are going in.
看看我们运气怎么样
Let's see what kind of luck we have.
- 看来不行 - 的确
- That's not the way. - Evidently not.
这不是个普通的机器，舰长
This is no ordinary machine, captain.
它已经具备了基本的智力
It may well possess a rudimentary intelligence.
但是它需要频繁进食
But it needs to eat. Frequently.
所以它应该没多少动力储备
So it can't have any great power reserves.
基本没什么用处
That may not be of any help.
进取号只有10个小时来突出重围
The Enterprise has only ten hours left in which to break free.
对
Yeah.
如果瓦尔在进食期间醒来会怎样？
What happens if Vaal weakens around feeding time?
史波克，检查一下天体物理实验室的电磁场
Spock, check the electromagnetic section of the astrophysics lab.
估算一下影响星舰的
Get an estimate of the total amount of energy
总能量的大小
being expended against the ship.
- 每小时测量一次 - 明白
- Have them measure it hour by hour. - Acknowledged.
怎么了，吉姆？
What's going on, Jim?
瓦尔在进食
Mess call.
在我看来，这是互惠原则的一个绝佳的例子
In my view, a splendid example of reciprocity.
只有你那像计算机一样的瓦肯人大脑
It would take a computerised Vulcan mind such as yours
才能说出这番话
to make that kind of a statement.
医生，你坚持要用人类的标准来衡量非人类文化
Doctor, you insist on applying human standards to non-human cultures.
我要提醒你，人类只是银河系中的沧海一粟
I remind you that humans are only a tiny minority in this galaxy.
史波克，有些东西是绝对的
There are certain absolutes, Mr. Spock, and one of them
其中之一就是类人生物也有享受自由 不受环境制约的权利
is the right of humanoids to a free and unchained environment.
生活在能使人长大的地方的权利
The right to have conditions which permit growth.
他们也有选择
Another is their right to choose a system
适合自己的制度的权利
which seems to work for them.
吉姆，你就打算这么
Jim, you're not just gonna stand by
眼睁睁的看着我们俩争执吗？
and be blinded to what's going on here?
他们是有智力的类人生物，需要进化成长
These are humanoids, intelligent. They need to advance and grow.
你没听懂吗？
Don't you understand what my readings indicate?
这里已经至少一万年没有任何变化和进步了
There's been no change or progress here in at least 10,000 years.
这不是生活，这是一潭死水
This isn't life. It's stagnation.
医生，这些人很健康，也很幸福
Doctor, these people are healthy and they are happy.
不管你怎么称呼这种制度，有什么想法
Whatever you choose to call it, this system works,
这制度对他们来说都很合适
despite your emotional reaction to it.
可能对你合适，史波克，可是对我来说不合适
It might work for you, Mr. Spock, but it doesn't work for me.
这些人活着就是为了伺候一台机器
Humanoids living so they can service a hunk of tin.
两位，我想你们还是等我们的星舰
Gentlemen, I think this philosophical argument can wait
脱离危险之后再进行这番理性讨论吧
until our ship is out of danger.
- 寇克收到 - 我是史考特，舰长
- Kirk here. - Scotty, sir.
我们判断了史波克说的能量来源
We have a reading on the power source Mr. Spock requested.
我们监控它时，它在产生往复循环
When we first monitored, it was generating alternating cycles
总计100的20次方沃瑟姆
totalling 100 to the 20th power Wortham units.
还在继续吗，史考特？
Did it maintain, Scotty?
不是，能量在一点点流失，不多，但是有
No, sir. Power's dropping bit by bit. Nominal, but a definite drain.
很好，继续监视
Good. Keep monitoring.
电路转换进行的怎么样了？
How are you coming along with the circuit switch-over?
除了厨房水槽，别的东西我全投进脉冲引擎了
We're putting everything but the kitchen sink into impulse power.
还要8个小时才能完成
It'll take us another eight hours to complete the work.
时间很紧啊，史考特
That's cutting it a bit fine, Scotty.
是，可是如果我们不能突围…
Aye. But if we don't break out...
…我宁愿不要等那么久
...l'd rather we didn't have to wait too long for the end of it.
完毕
Kirk out.
我一想到进取号要完蛋，而我们又…
Every time I think of the Enterprise burning up and us...
文书，你这是在浪费精力
Yeoman, you're wasting energy.
- 舰长，我们被困在… - 坐下，吃点东西吧
- Captain, we're trapped... - Sit down and have something to eat.
- 进取号还在上面… - 这不还没有发生嘛
- The Enterprise is up there... - That hasn't happened yet.
我在想会发生什么…
I wonder what would happen...
文书，推测一下
Yeoman, speculate.
如果这个星球上有人死了怎么办？
What would happen if someone on this planet died?
这不可能啊，你说瓦尔保他们长生不死
But they can't. You said that Vaal takes care of them.
总有意外发生啊
Accidents happen.
没错
Yes.
我想如果有人失足掉下悬崖之类的事情发生
I suppose if someone were to fall off a cliff or something,
会影响到人口的平衡吧
that might upset the balance of the population.
他们就需要添丁了
Then they would need a replacement.
有什么想法吗？史波克
They'd need a replacement. Opinion, Mr. Spock?
看来是别无选择了
I see no alternative.
可是这些人…
But these people...
我是说，他们不懂得…
I mean, if they don't know anything about...
就是说，他们应该是不会自然地…
What I mean is, they don't seem to have any natural...
那要怎么办呢？
I mean, how is it done?
史波克先生，你是科学官
Mr. Spock, you're the science officer.
你来跟这位女士解释一下吧
Why don't you explain it to the young lady?
恩，我想可以猜想…
Well, I believe it's safe...
他们也会接受必要的…
Safe to assume that they would receive the necessary...
…指示
...instructions.
接受一个机器的指示？
From a machine?
我倒想看看
That I'd like to see.
我明白，瓦尔
I understand, Vaal.
我会完成的
It shall be done.
如果不是因为瓦尔，这里一定就是天堂了
You know, if it weren't for Vaal, this place would be a paradise.
我们在一起的地方，就是天堂
Any place we can be together is paradise.
帕维
Pav,
星舰真的能逃出来吗？
can the ship really break away?
我不知道
I don't know.
我们还能回到星舰上吗？
Will we be able to get back aboard?
玛莎，我不知道
Martha, I don't know.
不过就算我们不得不留在这里
But if we do have to stay here,
也不会太坏啊
would it be so very bad?
有你在就不会
No, not if you're with me.
- 你怎么看起来怪怪的？ - 他们相互触摸…
- Why do you look like that? - The way they touched...
我不理解
I do not understand.
他们没有生气，而且看起来很愉快的样子
They were not angry. I think it was pleasant for them.
可是他们得到了什么呢？
But what is to be gained?
又不是跳舞
It is not a dance.
也没有收集食物，更没有侍奉瓦尔
It gathers no food. It does not serve Vaal.
不过他们看起来确实…
But it did seem as though it was...
…十分愉快
...pleasant to them.
确实很愉快，马库拉
It is pleasant, Makora.
是的
Yes.
他们这样彼此触碰
They touched in this way.
瓦尔！瓦尔发怒了
Vaal! He is angry.
规矩很清楚
The law is plain.
我已经向你们传达了瓦尔的旨意
I have given you the words of Vaal.
难道你们自愿遭天谴吗？
Do you beg the lightning to strike?
我们看到那两个陌生人这么做
We saw the strangers, the two of them, do this thing.
- 你模仿他们？ - 我们没有恶意
- You copied them? - We meant no harm.
瓦尔说的没错，新来的人确实很危险
Vaal speaks truly to me. The newcomers are a danger.
告诉瓦尔的子民，等那些陌生人睡着后
Tell the men of Vaal to meet me in the clear place
来洁净之地见我
when the strangers are asleep.
这是瓦尔亲口说的
It is Vaal's own words.
瓦尔已经告诉了我，他说的没错
Vaal has spoken to me. His words are true. Hear them.
我们要杀了那些陌生人
We are to kill the strangers.
“杀”，阿古他？
"Kill," Akuta?
我们不明白
We do not understand.
这是必须要做的，就像侍奉瓦尔进食一样
It is a thing to do, like feeding Vaal.
瓦尔向我解释过，我给你们展示一下
Vaal explained it to me. I will show you.
这是某个陌生人的头部
This is the head of one of the strangers.
找个粗棍子
Find a heavy stick,
走到陌生人身后，然后这样
come up from behind the stranger, and do this:
很简单的，这是瓦尔的旨意
It is a simple thing. It is the word of Vaal.
在明天日出之前
It will be done, to all of them...
…就要全部完成
...when the sun returns in the morning.
舰长，我在担心
I am concerned, captain.
这里也许不是理想社会，但却是个可行的社会
This may not be an ideal society, but it is a viable one.
老骨头说的对，他们不是在生活，只是存在而已
Bones was right. These people aren't living, they're existing.
他们不创造，不生产，甚至都不思考
They don't create, they don't produce, they don't even think.
他们存在就为了伺候一台机器
They exist to service a machine.
在我看来，如果我们做了貌似必须要做的事
If we do what it seems we must, in my opinion,
那就违反了不干涉指令
we'll be in direct violation of the Non-lnterference Directive.
他们是人，不是机器人
These are people, not robots.
他们有选择的权利
They should have the opportunity of choice.
我们不应干涉他们
We owe it to them to interfere.
星际舰队指挥官可不这么想
Starfleet Command may think otherwise.
我要试一试
I'll take my chances.
你出去看看吧
Why don't you have a look around?
寇克呼叫进取号，史考特先生
Kirk to Enterprise. Mr. Scott.
- 在，舰长 - 怎么样了，史考特
- Here, sir. - How's it going, Scotty?
快了，舰长，再有半个小时就可以了
Almost ready, sir. We'll need a half an hour yet.
你知道，再有45分钟
You realise that within 45 minutes,
我们就要被拖进大气层了吧
the ship will be pulled down into the atmosphere.
我知道，你说过时间很紧
I know that. As you said, it's cutting things fine.
- 是的，我… - 舰长
- Yes, l... - Captain.
完毕
Kirk out.
- 怎么了？ - 很奇怪
- What is it? - Disturbing.
瓦尔的子民们好像都消失了
The People of Vaal seem to have disappeared.
小心力场，舰长
Force field, captain.
瓦尔
Vaal.
我们是带着和平使命而来
We are on a peaceful mission.
我们无意伤害你和你的子民
We mean no harm to you or your people.
脉冲有变化，舰长，我想它在检查我们
Variation in impulses, captain. I believe it is reading us.
所有波段都出现强烈暴跌
Strong jump on all wavelengths.
快走！
Let's get out of here!
老骨头！
Bones!
二级烧伤
Second-degree burns.
不严重，看来他们很聪明
Not serious, but I bet they smart.
医生，你轻描淡写的天赋无人能及啊
Doctor, you have an unsurpassed talent for understatement.
马普尔！
Marple!
把他们关进小屋
Put them in the hut.
找到女人们在哪里，让她们也进去
Find out where the women are, put them in there too.
好好医生还在关心
The good doctor was concerned
瓦尔人达到真正人类的高度
that the Vaalians achieve true human stature.
我想着没什么好担心的
I submit there is no cause for worry.
看来他们已经走出了第一步
They've taken the first step.
学会杀人了
They've learned to kill.
我们准备好了，舰长
We're ready here, sir.
所有能用上的动力都投入了脉冲引擎
All available power has been channelled into the impulse engines.
还有12分钟就要进入大气层了
We have 12 minutes before entering atmosphere.
很好，史考特，反推力全开，挣脱出去
All right, Scotty, put her in full reverse. Get her out of there.
反推力全开，卡尔，所有引擎打开
Full reverse, Mr. Kyle, all engines.
长官！
Sir!
舰长，我们正在脱离！
Captain, we're doing it, we're pulling away!
史考特，怎么了？
Scotty, what happened?
不妙啊，舰长，只有少数几个系统有反应
It's no good, sir. There's only a few systems responding.
舰长，远离了一点点
Captain, we pulled away a little.
争取了大概一个小时
We gained maybe an hour.
但是几乎投入了所有
But we blew almost every system in the ship doing it.
没有资本再试一次了
There's nothing left to try again.
看来你得解雇我了，舰长
I guess you'll have to fire me, sir.
你被解雇了
You're fired.
- 400人啊 - 吉姆
- Four hundred people. - Jim.
就因为我没有意识到危险，他们便要付出生命
They'll die because I couldn't see a warning sign.
我不得不遵守命令，永远是命令
I had to follow orders. Always orders.
- 进去 - 该敲进食钟了
- Get back in there. - Fine time to ring the dinner bell.
进去，马上
Get back in there. Now.
- 老骨头，这么办 - 进去
- Bones, that's it. - Get back in there.
跟契诃夫一起
Stay with Chekov.
别让那些人去给瓦尔喂食
Keep those people from feeding Vaal.
别让他们喂瓦尔，让他们呆在小屋里
Don't let them feed Vaal. Keep them in the hut.
史波克先生
Mr. Spock.
史考特，相位炮还有能量吗？
Scotty, do you still have phaser power?
- 有，可是…？ - 全部用上
- Aye, but what..? - Lock all banks
锁定地表的能量场
on the coordinates of the energy field down here.
听我命令，准备攻击这一坐标
On my command, commence firing on those coordinates.
是，舰长，可是相位炮也无法穿透力场啊
Aye, sir, but they won't penetrate that force field.
如果我的猜测正确，就不用穿透力场，准备
If my guess is correct, they won't have to. Stand by.
瓦尔在呼唤我们，让我们去侍奉他吧，瓦尔饿了
Vaal calls to us. Let us go to him. He hungers.
求你们了
Please.
读数下降了，舰长
Readings are getting weaker, captain.
能量传送出现剧烈变动
Wide variation in energy transmissions,
看来瓦尔想要汲取其他能量
as though Vaal were trying to draw on other sources.
- 只能用电池了是吧？ - 看来是的
- Tapping its energy cells? - I would assume so.
很好，星舰挣脱的时候肯定挫伤了它的力量
Good. The ship's pulling away must have weakened it considerably.
它必须得进食
It has to be fed,
但它的能量储备还能坚持几天
but its reserve capacity could hold out for days.
它要加强力场以抵御相位炮攻击的话
If it had to reinforce its energy field to ward off a phaser attack,
就要大量利用储备能量
it would have to draw more heavily on its reserves.
这就是我的计划，史考特
My plan exactly. Scotty.
收到
Scott here, sir.
史考特，开始攻击，不要停
Scotty, commence firing, and maintain.
卡尔先生，打开所有相位炮，开火
Mr. Kyle. All phasers, commence firing.
能量产生有大幅度增加，舰长
Tremendous upsurge in generated power, captain.
看来，瓦尔想要加强自己的能量场
Obviously, Vaal is trying to reinforce its energy field.
很好，看看它能坚持多久
Good. Let's see how long he can do it.
史考特！停火！
Scotty! Cease fire!
没有能量产生了，舰长
No power generation at all, captain.
瓦尔死了
Vaal is dead.
史考特，报告情况
Mr. Scott, status report.
牵引光束消失了，反物质隔舱又有效能了
Tractor beam gone. Potency returning to antimatter pods.
我马上打开所有引擎以恢复回路
I'll have all engineering sections working on the circuits immediately.
一小时之内传送设备就可以准备妥当
Transporter will be ready in an hour.
史考特，你官复原职
Scotty, you're rehired.
传送器一修好
As soon as the transporter's fixed,
就组装一台带全套分析装置的设备
form an engineering detail with full analytical equipment
传送给我们，完毕
and beam them down. Kirk out.
契诃夫，老骨头，放了那些人吧
Chekov. Bones. Let those people go.
可是是瓦尔让树上结出果实
But it was Vaal who put the fruit on the trees,
让甘霖降落大地
caused the rain to fall.
瓦尔…
Vaal...
…关心我们
...cared for us.
你们会学着自己照顾自己，在我们的帮助下
You'll learn to care for yourselves, with our help.
植物开花结果也没有什么技巧
And there's no trick to putting fruit on trees.
你们会喜欢的
You might even enjoy it.
你们会学会如何为自己建造房屋
You'll learn to build for yourselves,
自己思考，为自己而劳动
think for yourselves, work for yourselves,
你们创造的东西都属于你们自己
and what you create is yours.
这就是我们所说的“自由”，你们会喜欢的，会非常喜欢
That's what we call freedom. You'll like it, a lot.
你们也会学会有关男女的知识
And you'll learn something about men and women,
男女本来应有的模样
the way they're supposed to be.
即关心彼此，因为拥有彼此而幸福
Caring for each other, being happy with each other.
善待彼此
Being good to each other.
这就是我们所说的“爱”
That's what we call love.
你们也会喜欢这个的，你们还有你们的孩子
You'll like that too, a lot. You and your children.
孩子是什么？
What are children?
像你们一样，小一点的，他们…
Little ones. Look like you. They...
顺其自然，你们就会明白
Just go on the way you're going, you'll find out.
我完全不同意你说的，史波克
I don't agree with you at all, Mr. Spock.
你经常不同意我说的，医生
That's not unusual, doctor.
嘿，吉姆，你来听一听
Hey, Jim, I want you to hear this.
舰长，我不确定我们在三角座γ六号的
Captain, I'm not at all certain we did the correct thing
所作所为是正确的
on Gamma Trianguli VI.
我们让那些人走上了社会演进的正轨
We put those people back on a normal course of social evolution.
有什么问题
I see nothing wrong in that.
那是一堂很好的实物教学课啊，史波克
Well, that's a good object lesson, Mr. Spock.
很好的说明了，机器管的太多时
An example of what can happen when a machine gets too efficient,
会发生什么
does too much work for you.
舰长，你知道圣经创世纪里面的故事吧
Captain, you are aware of the biblical story of Genesis.
当然知道
Yes, of course I'm aware of it.
亚当和夏娃吃了苹果
Adam and Eve tasted the apple,
结果，他们被逐出了伊甸园
and as a result, were driven out of paradise.
正是，舰长
Precisely, captain.
某种意义上来说，我们给了瓦尔人那只苹果
And, in a manner of speaking, we have given the People of Vaal the apple,
也可以说，善恶的知识
the knowledge of good and evil, if you will,
作为结果，他们也被逐出了伊甸园
as the result of which they, too, have been driven out of paradise.
医生，你说我理解的对不？
Doctor, do I understand him correctly?
你是说我扮演了撒旦的角色吗？
Are you casting me in the role of Satan?
不是这样的，舰长
Not at all, captain.
咱们星舰上有谁长得哪怕…
Is there anyone on this ship who even remotely...
…有一点点像撒旦吗？
...looks like Satan?
我没有发现符合这一描述的人，舰长
I am not aware of anyone who fits that description, captain.
确实没有，史波克
No, Mr. Spock, I didn't think you would be.
TLF字幕组欢迎你，欢迎有志之士加入
TLF微博http://weibo.com/tlfsubs/
TLF中文字幕站http://tlfsubs.eastgame.org/